A Finding Aid to the Signa Gallery Records, 1957-1963, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Signa Gallery records
1957-1963
Archives of American Art
Signa Gallery
AAA.signgall
Archival Resource Key
1.4 Linear feet
The records of the Signa Gallery measure 1.4 linear feet and date from 1957 to 1963. The records document the history of the gallery through administrative files; correspondence; guestbooks, artist biographies, and photographs of Franz Kline paintings and exhibition opening; exhibition files for exhibits at the gallery; insurance documents, ledgers, invoices, and other financial records; clippings, ehixibition announcements and catalogs, and other printed material.
Biographical / Historical
The Signa Gallery was founded in 1957 with the purpose of exhibiting the works of contemporary East Hampton, N.Y. artists. Alfonso Ossorio was one of the founding members and owners of the gallery.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series.
Series 1: Administrative Files, 1957-1963 (0.4 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Exhibition Files, 1957-1960 (0.3 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 3: Financial Records, 1957-1963 (0.6 linear feet; Boxes 1-2)
Series 4: Printed Material, 1957-1960 (0.1 linear feet; Box 2)
Scope and Contents
The records of the Signa Gallery measure 1.4 linear feet and date from 1957 to 1963. The records document the history of the gallery through administrative files; correspondence; guestbooks, artist biographies, and photographs of Franz Kline paintings and exhibition opening; exhibition files for exhibitions at the gallery; insurance documents, ledgers, invoices, and other financial records; clippings, ehixibition announcements and catalogs, and other printed material.
Administrative files are comprised of a lease for the gallery and a certificate of incorporation for the gallery. Correspondence is between gallery managers Alfonso Ossorio, Elizabeth Parker, and John Little and other galleries, business associates, and artists, including Fritz Bultman, Philip Guston, and Jack Tworkov. Guestbooks and notes include a guestbook and an address book for the gallery, various artist biographies, and some miscellaneous notes. Also included are a file of photographs of exhibition openings, and a file of photographs of Franz Kline paintings.
Exhibitions and Lecture files are comprised of photographs, press material, and correspondence related to exhibitions at the gallery. Also included are a series of lectures and two untranscribed audio tape reels that accompany one of the lectures.
Financial material includes insurance documents, bank records such as checking accounts, invoices, consignments, and some ledgers.
Printed material is made up of newspaper clippings, exhibition announcements, and exhibition catalogs.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Researchers interested in accessing audiovisual recordings in this collection must use access copies. Contact References Services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated 1981 by Alfonso A. Ossorio, one of the initial founders and owners of the gallery.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection are available on 35mm microfilm reels 3983-3984 at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.
Art galleries, Commercial -- New York (State); Sound recordings; Ossorio, Alfonso, 1916-1990
- Administrative Files, 1957-1963; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  Administrative files are comprised of a lease for the gallery and a certificate of incorporation for the gallery. Correspondence is between gallery managers Alfonso Ossorio, Elizabeth Parker, and John Little and other galleries, business associates, and artists, including Fritz Bultman, Philip Guston, and Jack Tworkov. Guestbooks and notes include a guestbook and an address book for the gallery, various artist biographies, and some miscellaneous notes. Also included are a file of photographs of exhibition openings, and a file of photographs of Franz Kline paintings.
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lease, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Guestbook, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Attendance Records, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Address Book, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Artist Biographies, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Franz Kline Paintings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Gallery Openings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Exhibition and Lecture Files, 1957-1960; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 1
  Exhibitions and Lecture files are comprised of photographs, press material, and correspondence related to exhibitions at the gallery. Also included are a series of lectures and two audio tape reels that accompany one of the lectures.
  - Exhibitions 1-4 and "Review of the Season", 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "The Artists' Vision" Exhibition, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "The Evocative Eye" Exhibition, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "The Human Image" Exhibition, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "An International Selection" Exhibition, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "The Animate Space" Exhibition, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Second Exhibition of 1959, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Third Exhibition of 1959, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Opening Exhibition of 1960, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Second Exhibition of 1960, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Third Exhibition of 1960, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Courtyard Art Festival", 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Greece Through an Artist's Eye" Lecture, 1959 July 10; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Signa Gallery Art Symposium", 1959 July 17; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bucminster Fuller Lecture, 1959 August 28; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Critic's Panel" Lecture, 1959 September; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound tape reels (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Tape reels are untranscribed.
- Financial Material, 1957-1963; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Financial material includes insurance documents, bank records such as checking accounts, invoices, consignments, and some ledgers.
  - Insurance: Edward F. Cook, 1957-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Insurance: Harvey Eigenfeld, 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Income Tax, 1957-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Checking Account, 1957-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37-47)
  - Account Book, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Petty Cash Ledger, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Invoices for Gallery Expenses, 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50-53)
  - Invoices for Gallery Expenses, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Paint Sales Records, 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sales Ledger, 1958-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sales Receipts, 1957-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Consigned Stock, circa 1957-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Consignment Receipts, 1958-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8-11)
- Printed Material, 1967-1960; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 0.1 Linear feet Box 2
  Printed material is made up of newspaper clippings, exhibition announcements, and exhibition catalogs.
  - Clippings, undated, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1957-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13-16)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)